Junaid Ahmad

Web Developer and Designer

0470478860

②

junaid.ahmad7@hotmail.com



https://au.linkedin.com/in/junaid-ahmad



https://junaidahmad7.github.io/portfolio



https://github.com/JunaidAhmad7

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a highly competent IT professional with over 2 years of experience as a front-end developer, developing modern web applications that function across all modern web browsers, on multiple devices. With a passion for front-end development and an interest in backend development, my goal is to create elegant digital experiences that can greatly benefit other people and organisations.

CORE SKILLS

Technical Skills

Languages and Libraries:

• HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, PHP, Python, MySQL, Oracle, Java, Processing

Content Management Systems:

WordPress

Source Control:

• Git, GitHub

Soft Skills

Qualities:

- Strong initiative and prioritisation
- Confident team member, flexible, and willing to take on tasks with minimal supervision
- Effective communication and engagement with others
- Ability to work under pressure with poise and meet deadlines
- Well-developed organisational and time management skills

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

February 2017 - Present

Junior Web Developer

Coral Active Sydney, NSW Achievements:

- Encouraged an MVP approach to Javascript development, resulting in cleaner code and reduced merge conflicts
- Communicated with team members effectively as a project leader, for which the deadline was met
- Documented a custom Javascript library with detailed code samples, resulting in more efficient development

April 2016 – December 2016

Web Developer/Designer Intern

Digital Fuel Marketing Limited Sydney, NSW

Duties:

- Building landing pages for stakeholders using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and Bootstrap 3
- Making changes to the Digital Fuel website
- Creating HTML5 animated ad banners using Google Web Designer

March 2016 - April 2016

Webmaster Intern

Medteryx Sydney, NSW Achievements:

- Implemented design changes to company website using WordPress
- Significantly reduced loading time of the website by 75%
- Made the company website operable across modern browsers

EDUCATION

2014 - 2016

Bachelor of Information Technology

Macquarie University North Ryde, NSW, Australia

- Majored in Web Design and Development
- GPA of 3.75/4.0
- Designed & developed 'Psst' a micro-blogging website
 - o http://junaidahmad.pythonanywhere.com
- Designed & developed 'The Game Genre Lounge'
 - http://home.ica.net/~ahmadm/junaid/index.ht
 ml
- Designed & developed 'Batman Dark Knight Dark City'
 - o http://home.ica.net/~ahmadm/batman

REFEREES

Oliver Liebscher Shelley McConaghy

Head of Design Client Services Manager

Digital Fuel Marketing Limited Medteryx

0478495718 0412 919 136

Junaid Ahmad 0470478860 2